# Kyle Kearney

## hello@kyleswork.com | kyleswork.com

# Summary

Motivated Front End Developer with 3 years of experience building modern and responsive user experiences. Highly capable in modern front end technologies such as React, Javascript, Wordpress, HTML5 / CSS3, plus a deep understanding of Adobe Illustrator, XD, and Photoshop. Passionate about writing, efficient, maintainable code to build awesome websites and applications.

# Professional Experience

# Front End Developer

Freelance I 2019 - Present I Englewood, CO

Being freelance I work along side teams of all sizes, and many different project management styles. Some of my responsibilities as a freelance Front End Developer have included:

- Partner with Marketing teams to deliver new user interactions and conversion features.
- Develop and update client Wordpress sites.
- Understand and utilize the latest tools, technologies, and trends to keep web apps modern.
- Design and develop new and enhanced features to improve the user experience.
- Architect & develop new frameworks and components for client applications.

## Front End Developer

Carbon Studio | 2017 - 2019 | Denver, CO

Carbon is a web development agency tailored towards small business clients, and sub contracting under other agencies. As the Front End Developer my responsibilities included:

- Communicate with clients and project owners to understand project requirements.
- Support in the process for setting up hosting and database for web applications.
- Produce high quality, pragmatic, reusable components on schedule.
- Write well tested, well organized, human focused code.
- Support the launch of websites and click funnels.

#### IT Consultant

Denver IT Consultants | 2016 - 2017 | Denver, CO

Denver IT Consultants is a IT firm focused around managing medium to large scale business's IT infrastructure. As a IT Consult my responsibilities included:

- Partner with system administrators to maintain network performance and reliability.
- Develop online ticket system to maintain and track client requests and employee resources.
- Setup network and hosting for client databases and websites.
- Build and maintain computer and network infrastructure.
- Increase average client network uptime from 94.4% to 98.9%.

#### Education

### Certificate - Full Stack Development

B.S. Computer Science

University of Denver - 2018

Colorado State University - 2021

#### Skills

React.js (3 years) | Javascript ES6 / ES7 (3 years) | Vue.js (3 years) | NPM / Node (3 years)

Git (3 years) | Node (3 years) | HTML5 / CSS3 (2 years) | SCSS (2 years) | Redux (2 years) | Typescript (1 year)